本字幕由 首发字幕组 - 真中 原创翻译
www.btshoufa.com
米歇尔，请不要挂电话
Michelle, please don't hang up.
跟我聊聊好吗？
Just talk to me, okay?
我很难相信你就这样离开了
I can't believe you just left.
米歇尔
Michelle
回来吧
Come back.
说一下话好吗
Please say something.
米歇尔？跟我说说话
Michelle?  Talk to me.
听着，我们之前有争论，夫妻吵架
Look, we had an argument, couples fight, that is ..
但没有任何理由就这样撇下所有事情不管啦
No reason to just leave everything behind.
逃避是解决不了问题的，米歇尔，求你了
Running away isn't going to help anything. Michelle, please ..
今天其他消息，南方海滨许多城市仍然没有恢复供应电力
Elsewhere today, power has still not been restored to many cities on the Southern seaboard.
这次大范围停电是从今天下午开始的
In the wake of this afternoon's widespread blackout..
该地区会有狂风暴雨的袭击
There has been some inclement weather in the region,
看来问题是跟灾难性的天气到来有关了
Problems seem linked to what authorities are calling a catastrophic power surge.
该地区交通陷入一片混乱
That has crippled traffic in the area.
科洛弗道10号
10 CLOVERFIELD LANE
没有信号
'NO SIGNAL'
好的好的，求你了
Okay, ok .. please.
求你了
Please ..
求你不要伤害我
Please don't hurt me.
求你了
Please,
放了我吧？我发誓我不会告诉任何人的
Just let me go, okay? I won't tell anybody, I promise.
求你放了我吧，求你了
Please just let me go.  Please.
你需要打点滴
You need fluids.
你受了点震荡
You were in shock.
你要对我做什么？
What're you going to do to me?
我会让你生存下去
I'm going to keep you alive.
走路用这个会方便点
Walk on getting handy with these.
我的男朋友在等着我
My boyfriend was expecting me.
他会找警察来找我的
He'll send the cops looking.
很抱歉
I'm sorry ..
但是没有人在找你
But no one is looking for you.
你搞了些对抗
You got some fight in you.
我很欣赏
I can respect that.
但别想着再来一次了
But don't even think about trying that again.
你来到这里真的很幸运
You're lucky to be here at all.
我的容忍度也是...有限的
My generosity only extends .. so far.
鸡蛋
Eggs,
泰勒诺（药名）会减轻你的疼痛
Tylenol to help with your pain.
求你了，求你放了我吧
Please .. please .. just let me go.
求你了...没地方可以去了，米歇尔
- Please. - There's nowhere to go, Michelle.
这眼神看起来不错嘛
That looks pretty well.
鉴于这是我救了你，我认为这是可以接受的
Given it as how I saved your life, I think that's acceptable.
你来到这里真的很幸运
You're lucky to be here at all.
你什么意思？我发现了你
- What do you mean? - I found you.
我救了你，带你来到这里
And I saved your life, by bringing you here.
我不明白
I don't understand,
之前遭到了袭击
There's been an attack.
什么？
What?
有袭击，很大型的
An attack. A big one.
我不确定是化学攻击，还是核攻击
I'm not sure yet if it's chemical, or nuclear.
但是我们在这里是安全的
But down here we're safe.
我们这是在哪里？
And where are we, exactly?
在我农场房子的下面
Underneath my farmhouse.
查尔斯湖外40英里远的地方
40 miles outside of Lake Charles.
我...我在这里的北面开车。-你发生意外了
- I ..  was driving north of here. - You were in an accident.
你在路边翻车了，我路过看到你
You were turned over on the side of the road. I was driving by, and I saw you.
我救了你，米歇尔
I saved your life, Michelle.
我不能就那样不管你
I couldn't just leave you there.
非常感谢你救了我
Thank you so much, for saving my life.  I ..
我想，我现在应该去医院
I guess I should, I should go to a hospital, now.
你不能走
You can't leave.
因为这次的袭击
An attack means all of them.
地面的空气被污染了，就因为此
Which contaminates the air above ground. That's, that's how it works.
我们还要等多久才会安全？
How, how long do we have to wait until it's safe?
根据最近一次爆炸的情况，一年，可能两年吧
Depends on the proximity to the closest blast. One year, maybe two.
而且那只是我们刚说到的知道的武器
And that's if we're, we're talking about weapons that we know of.
俄罗斯人发明了些肮脏的武器，而如果火星人终于找到了这里来
Russians were developing some nasty stuff. And if the martians finally found a way to get here.
他们的武器会让我们的核武器看起来像棍子和石头一样
Their weapons will, will make our nukes look like, like sticks and stones.
幸运的是
Luckily,
我准备了这一切
I prepared for this.
我想借用一下你手机
I need to use your phone, then,
打给我家人，告诉他们我在这里很安全
To call my family. And, and tell them that I'm safe here.
然后确认一下他们也是安全的。-米歇尔，他们不安全
- And make sure they're okay. - Michelle, they're not okay.
你怎么知道？
How do you know that?
在外面的人全都死了
Everyone outside of here is dead.
你呢？你没有家人吗？
What about you? Don't you have a family?
没有
No
那是谁？
Who's that?
失礼一下
Excuse me.
你干了些什么？
What did you do?
等等
Wait.
你知道吗，米歇尔？我要跟你说，我和他说了些什么
You know what, Michelle? I'm going to tell you, what I told him..
你需要吃的，你需要睡觉
You need to eat, you need to sleep,
而且你需要对我表示一些感激
And you need to start showing me a little bit of appreciation.
我名字是霍华德
My name is Howard, by the way.
天啊，糟了
God, oh shit.
很对不起
I'm sorry,
抱歉什么。我不是故意...
Sorry about that.  I didn't mean to ..
吓你
Scare you.
你，呃，你饿吗？
You, hmm,  hmm, you hungry?
你还好吗？没事吧？
So how're you doing, huh?  You okay?
这是什么？
What is this?
是个仓库
It's a bunker.
你房间天花装的好点，但...
Your room is a bit of a fixer-upper, but ..
至少你还有门
At least you got the door.
一扇可怕的门，但你至少有门
A scary door, but you still got the door.
你来这里多久了？
How long have you been down here?
几天吧，我想。你知道，这很难说
A couple of days, I think.  You know, it's actually kind of hard to tell.
没有窗户、阳光，还有其他东西
No windows, the sunlight, and everything.
我意思是，我们怎么离开这里？
I mean, how do we get out of here?
他没告诉你吗？
He didn't tell you?
关于...
About ..
离开这里是你最不愿意做的事
Getting out of here, is the last thing you want to do.
因为外面的空气
Cause the air out there,
都被污染了
It's contaminated.
我看你遇上艾米特了
I see you've met Emmett
他发生什么事了？他自己干的事
- What happened to him? - He did that to himself.
他在这里发脾气没有任何帮助
And his stumbling around isn't helping anything.
你之前听到的
What you heard earlier,
就是他撞翻了架子，上面有一个星期的粮食
Was him knocking over a shelf with a whole week's worth of food.
他很过意不去的，是吧？
Which he's sorry for, correct?
非常
Totally.
走吧，上厕所时间
Let's go.  Bathroom time.
这是公共区域，娱乐休息用的
This is the common area.  Good for R&R.
如你所见，我已经做好打算在这常住了
As you can see, I've planned for a long stay.
空气净化器会净化空气保持新鲜
The applaponic system cleans the air and keeps it fresh.
这是起居室，你自己想看什么书都随意
This is the living room. Help yourself to any reading.
如果你想看电影
If you like to watch films,
我有一些DVD和录像带
I have some on DVD and VHS cassette.
不过你看完后要把它放回原位
Just make sure you put them back in their sleeve when they're done.
厨房是多功能的。有电磁炉，冰库
The kitchen is fully functional. There's an electric stove, refrigerator.
冰箱，银器
Freezer, silverware.
这张桌子是我祖辈留下的，这是说你们要看管好你们的玻璃器物
And that table is a family heirloom, which means watch your glasses.
都要用杯托和餐具垫
Always use coasters and placemats.
缩开你的手！
Keep you hands to yourself!
明白吗？
Understand?
不要触碰
No touching.
坐下吧
Take a seat.
这边来
This way.
这是我的私人场所
This is my private space
除非有我允许，禁止入内
Off-limits, unless I give express permission.
你进去吧
Go ahead.
不，我不需要。但是你会
- Nah, I don't need to. - You will though.
我会整理一下这里的，所以请便
And I've got to pace these things out, so please.
我要上厕所。-就在靠近帘子那边
- I need privacy. - You're welcome to close the curtain.
你站在那我上不了
I can't with you standing there.
但我不能相信你不会烧了这个地方，这关乎我个人的安全
And I can't trust you not to burn this place down. This is for my own safety.
我不是那些...变态。去吧
I'm not some .. pervert.  Just go.
你搞定之前不要冲水
Don't flush unless you've gone.
不要浪费水
Can't afford wasting flushes.
找个凳子坐吧
Take a seat.
你饿不饿？
Are you hungry?
那些是美根的书
Those are Megan's.
她去哪都要带上两三件这东西
She never went anywhere without two or three of those things.
美根是谁？
Who's Megan?
美根已经死了
Megan's not with us anymore.
别担心，发电机而已
Don't worry.  Just the generator.
可能是辆车在外面
Maybe it's a car outside.
那不可能。-我听到过一次
- That's not possible. -  I heard one earlier.
就在我房间头顶
Above my room.
如果你真的听到，那司机现在肯定已经死了很久了
If you had heard a car, the driver would be long dead by now.
我们不应该尝试着打电话给警察吗？
Shouldn't we at least try .. to call the police?
要有人查查到底发生了什么事？-没有人可以求救了
- Someone to find out what actually happened? - There's no one left to call.
看到没？没有东西能穿进来
See that?  Nothing's coming through.
你认为我是个疯子
You think I sound crazy.
这很让人惊讶，你们这些人
It's amazing, you people..
你们骑车时会戴头盔，开车就戴安全带
You wear helmets when you ride your bikes, you have seat-belts,
在家里装个警报系统来保护房子
You're in your cars, you have alarm systems to protect your homes.
但如果那些警报失效了，你会做什么呢？
But what do you do when those alarms go off?
洪水来了你才造船那才叫疯了
Crazy, is building your ark after the flood is already come.
我想现在是时候让你见见弗兰克和米尔德
I think now might be time you met Frank and Mildred.
这是我离空气锁最近的了
Closest I can get to in airlock.
看到没？
See?
他们发生什么事了？
What happened to them?
它们不像你这么幸运
They weren't as lucky as you.
是因为空气，米歇尔
It's the air, Michelle.
如果你出去了就会变成那样
That's what happens when you get exposed.
我把这扇门给封了，全天候的
I keep this door sealed, at all times.
没有人能进或出
No one comes in or out.
看到了弗兰克和米尔德了吧？
Met Frank and Mildred, huh?
这很有趣对吧？
It's funny, right?
世界末日了，但他最难过的是一对死猪
The whole world ends.  And the thing's he's most upset about is a pair of dead pigs.
你要看点书吗？
You gonna need some .. uh, reading material.
都烂成这样，不好意思
That's all there is, sorry.
我想学一下怎么弄个法式辫子
My idea of how to learn to do a french braid, so..
如果你想让我帮你扎的话，你跟我说一声
If you want me to do that for you, just let me know.
你知道他些什么东西？
What do you know about him?
他以前是海军的，我知道
He was in the Navy, I know that.
我想他是做卫星之类的活吧
I guess he did, uh, some stuff with satellites.
什么之类的活？
What kinds of stuff?
卫星...的东西
Satellite .. stuff.
那什么把他带来这的？
And what brought him out here?
我不知道
I'm not sure.
他买这房子有一段时间了
He bought this property a while back.
我从没注意过，知道他请我帮他盖好这里
I never paid much attention, until he hired me to help him get this place set up.
这份工，呃...
The work, was, uh..
蛮有趣的，这是肯定的
Entertaining, though, that's for sure.
你知道，霍华德阴谋论里的黑带
You know, Howard, is like a black belt in conspiracy theories.
而且，你知道，不会时常有人叫你建造世界末日避难所的
Plus, you know, how often do you get hired to build the doomsday bunker?
他，绑架你了？
He .. kidnapped you?
没有
No.
你的手臂怎么了？你是不是尝试着逃走？
What happened to your arm? You were trying to escape?
我是尝试着进来
I was trying to get in.
我看着霍华德建造这个地方，一点一点的，好多年了
And I watched Howard build this place, piece by piece, for years.
他经常说起些...
He was always talking about..
你知道，可能的袭击
you know, possible attacks,
阿尔盖答，俄罗斯，南韩
Al-Qeda, Russia, South Korea,
你指朝鲜吧？-是疯了的那个吗？
- You mean North Korea? - the, the.. is that the crazy one?
是的，就那个
Yeah, that one.  Hmm ..
你知道，把他所有钱都花在这上面，就像他的命就靠它了
And, hmm, you know. Pour all his money into this place, took to it, like his life depended on it.
你知道
Which,.. you know,
现在加上你了
That stays with you.
所以
So,
他告诉你这些
He told all this,
在你帮他建造这个避难所的时候
While you're building his bomb shelter,
现在他说
And now he says that ..
空气被污染了，全部人都死了
The air is contaminated, and everybody's dead.
是的，我知道你怀疑，但不止这些
Yeah, I know what you're getting at. But there's more to it.
霍华德绑架了我
Howard abducted me.
他把我撞出路边，然后把我拽来这里
He drove me off the road, and he dragged me here.
所以无论他告诉你些什么，空气
So whatever he's telling you about the .. air,
大型袭击，起避难所的目的，都是骗人的。-不，不是的
- Some big attack. The purpose of this shelter, is a lie. - No, no way.
那场袭击，我亲眼看到的
The attack, I saw it myself.
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
我下班途中
It's on my way from work,
像闪了一下
And, looked like a flash.
很亮的红光
Bright red,
像爆炸一样，很远的地方
Like an explosion, from way far off.
不像是烟花
Wasn't like fireworks,
不是的，它更像你在圣经里读到的
No, it was more this like something your read about in the bible.
如此你看到的是闪光？闪电？
So what you saw was a flashing light? Lightning?
燃尽一切的大火？-我...我也解释不清
- Fire that cleared up? - I'm not .. explaining it right.
这不像我曾经看到过的
This wasn't like anything I've ever seen.
这是我从没见过的
This was something I've never seen before
所以我直接来到这里了
So I came directly here.
当我来到这里，我只想让霍华德关上那门
When I came here, I wanted Howard just close the door.
我可以看得出，在他脸上，他知道发生什么了
I can see it,right there on his face, he knew something was happen.
一些可怕的事
Something bad.
所以我进来了
So I thought my way in.
我听到一辆车
I heard a car.
在我们上面
Above us.
你听到有人吗？-就在我们上面
Did you hear somebody? - Right above us.
那不可能
That's impossible.
空气...什么，被污染了？
Heaven is ... - What? Infective?
你怎么知道？-因为那是我说的
How do you know? - Because I said.
晚餐准备好了
The food is ready.
我看到你们两个相处得很好啊
I see you along.
果酱怎么样？
What is sauce?
还好吧。-说到厨艺，我还行的
It's fine. - Can I cook enough.
不是非常好，但是还可以。美根是个好厨师
Not good, but reasonable. Megan was a great cook.
你会学到一点烹饪技术
You will learn a little cooking.
很好吃啊。这是我吃过的最好吃的酱
Is awesome. The best I ever tasted sauce.
你在开玩笑吧？
Are you being funny?
不，我意思是
No, I mean ..
考虑到环境的改变，你知道
Considering the alternative, which is, you know..
被化学攻击，或者是核武器攻击后
Get burned up in a chemical attack, or nuclear ..
我还生存着，来到这里
I say being alive, and down here is ..
就算是炸便便也是非常美味的
It's made a fried turd taste pretty good, so..
所以是我吃过的最好的酱
Best damn sauce I ever had.
听起来有点道理，但请你注意一下餐桌语言
that sounds be a point, and please watch your language at the table.
好的
Right.
你知道我脑海中一直浮现一种东西，因为一些原因
You know what I haven't been able to get out of my head, for some reason.
自从我来到这里之后
Ever since I got down here,
纹身
Tatoos.
我一直想纹一个
I always wanted one.
但我从来没纹过。因为所有人都说不要啊，都说如果你纹了，就找不到一份好工作了
But I never got any.  Because everyone always said, nah, no, Emmett you'll never get a decent job if you do that.
管它呢
Whatever
看来现在可以纹了，对吧？
Like that matters now, right?
告诉你们，如果我知道会这样子，我早就纹它50个了
Tell you what, I had know this was coming, I'd gotten like 50 of them.
我就是这样
That's where I'm at.
我会看起来像个怪人，我会全身都纹遍，从头到脚趾
I would look like a circus freak or something. I would just be covered.  Head to toe, tattoos all over ..
全身都是，脸，衣服，就那，横过我前额
Everywhere, face, shirt, right there. Across my forehead.
就我的名字，艾米特
Just my name, Emmett.
或者，你知道
Or, you know..
“恶棍人生”
- "Thug Life" - [Michelle laughs]
YOLO
- 'YOLO'
我不知道这什么意思，但我听到别人总是说，所以这肯定是很酷的
I don't even know what that means, but, I hear people saying it all the time.  So it must be cool.
嘿，你呢，霍华德？
Hey, what about you, Howard?
你想做的都做完了吗？
Anything you wish you'd done?
老实说，没有
In all honesty, no.
没有？
No?
没想过去拉斯维加斯过一个疯狂的夜晚？
No crazy nights in Vegas?,
或者，去朝圣？
Maybe, ah, take a pilgrimage to Waco?
我想做的事情都做了
Everything I wanted to do, I did.
我只专注于准备
I focused on being prepared.
而我准备好了
And I was.
故我们才能在这里
And here we are.
噢，我的天啊
Oh, my goodness..
那是“独占”吗？
Is that Monopoly?
我们玩吧
There we go.
对了，我们可以消磨时间
Yeah, that's how we kill the time.
我意思是，你说什么来着？我们将会在这里生活一两年，还是三年？
I mean, what you say?  We're going to be down here like what, a year, two, three?
我打赌如果我们现在就开始玩，可能很快就可以结束了
Bet you if we started a game right now, we might even get halfway finished..
不要再说了
Stop talking!
你不必说些我们将会在这里呆多久的笑话
You don't need to make jokes about how long we're going to be down here.
没人知道我们将会呆多久
When nobody knows how long that's going to be.
你的笑话并不好笑
You humor is not funny.
我在吃东西的时候我不想你这样做，米歇尔也不想
I don't appreciate it while I'm trying to eat, and neither does Michelle.
现在请你闭嘴吧，让我们安静的吃
Now please shut up, and let us eat in peace.
艾米特？
Emmett?
帮我递张餐巾
Pass me a napkin.
我知道你所说的
I know what you're saying.
我从来没玩完过“独占”
I never could finish Monopoly.
那游戏没有终结的，是吧？
That game really does take forever, right?
对我来说，它是
For me though, it was .. hmm,
“斜坡和梯子”
'Chutes, and Ladders'.  Ahmm,
“抱歉”
'Sorry',
和“麻烦”
and 'Trouble'.
那有着骰子，你按着的那东西，叫什么来着？
And that thing with the dice, and that thing that you press, what is that called?
那是...“珀珀泡泡”，对对，没错
That,  that .. 'PoppleMatic Bubble!', yeah, right!
你曾经玩过“行动”吗？
You ever play that, what was it, 'Operation'?
噢，“行动”啊。-噢，我不能玩那游戏
- Oh 'Operation" - Oh, man, I couldn't play that game.
当你敲打边边的时候发出的噪音
That noise that thing would make when you hit that edge, when..
天啊。-那真够吓人的
- Good lord, - That was scary.
麻烦你递一下盐给我
Can you give me the salt?
请
Please?
啊，不好意思
Ah, shoot.  Sorry.
我还想要胡椒粉
I'm going to need the pepper also,
你想要干嘛？-我只想要胡椒粉而已
- What exactly do you think you're doing? - I'm just asking for the pepper.
去你的，那是什么东西？-我不知道你在说什么
- The hell you were?  What was that? - I don't know what you're talking about.
你是在侮辱我吗？
You trying to insult me?
在这个我建造的让你活下去的避难所里？
Here in a shelter that I built, that's keeping you alive?
你以为我看不到你所做的吗？
You don't think I see what you just did?
这就是我救了你的回报？
Is that how you thank me for saving your life?
冷静点-闭嘴
- Calm down. - Shut Up!
闭嘴！坐下来！
Shut Up!  And stay in your seat!
是这样吗？
Is it?
我告诉你吧
Let me tell you,
我知道背叛者是什么样子的
I know what a traitor looks like,
明白吗？
Understand?
我一直对你慷慨和大度
I have shown you nothing but generosity, and hospitality.
我要你道歉
I want you to apologize.
告诉我你会守规矩
And tell me you're going to behave.
我会
I will.
你会什么
You will what?
我会守规矩
I'll behave.
还有，我很抱歉
And I'm so sorry.
你必须保持头脑清醒
You have to stay hydrated.
在这里老容易忘记
It's easy to forget down here.
有什么问题吗
What's wrong?
没有
Nothing
我的钥匙呢？
Where are my keys?
米歇尔
Michelle!
停下
Stop!
把钥匙给我
Give me those keys!
开啊开啊-我要走啦
- Come on. - I'm going.
不不！
No! No!
不要！不要打开！
No! Don't do it!
不要！
No!
不要打开门！
Don't open that door!
那是辆车！
It's a car!
那是辆车！我看到一辆车！
It's a car!  I see a car!
这里！这里！
Here!  Here!
这里！
Here!
米歇尔！听我说，不要打开！
Michelle, listen to me, don't do it!
救命啊！
Help me!
有个女人-打开门
- There's a woman. - Open the door.
我只是想进来-她看起来受伤了，她想让我进来
- I just.. I want to come inside. - She looks hurt, she wants me to let her in!
不要让她进来
Do not let her in!
看看她的脸，米歇尔！
Look at her face, Michelle!
不要，不不不不
No, no, no .. no, no.
天啊 我没事
oh my god, I'm fine..
真的 我没事
I am really, I'm fine. I am ok.
我只是感染了一点点 开门 拜托
Just a little, oh , please open the door.
开门 她在求我
- Open it. - She's begging me!
你帮了不她
You can't help her!
没人可以 会没事的 我很好
- Nobody can. - It'll be okay.
我会没事的，我们都会
I'll be okay, all of us.
开门啊
Open the door!
不要听她的
Don't listen to her!
开门 婊子
Open the door, you bitch!
让我进去
Let me in!
让我进去!让我进去!让我进去!
Let me in!   Let me in!   Let me in!
快点！
Now!
快点快点！
Now.  Now!
快点！
Now!
开门
Open!
我知道这很难以接受
I know it's hard.
意识到他们都死掉了
Realizing they're all gone.
你爱的人
The ones you love.
我有些事要向你坦白
I have something to confess to you.
我撞了你的车
I crashed into your car.
你的事故
Your accident.
是我造成的
Was my fault.
当我知道袭击就要发生的时候 我发狂了
When I found out about the incoming attack, I got frantic.
我知道我要尽快回到这里
I knew I needed to get back here as soon as possible,
所以我开得像疯子一样
Oh, I was driving like a maniac,
我想要超你车
I tried to pass you, and..
车祸是我造成的
I'm the reason you went off the road.
我知道我看起来是一个理智的人
And I know I seem like a sensible guy,
但在那时候，我不是我
But, at the time, I wasn't myself.
那的确是个意外 但是是我的错
It was an accident.  But it was my fault.
我不敢告诉你
I was afraid to tell you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你该洗个澡了
You should shower,
缝隙里进来的一点点空气都可能有毒
You had the smallest amount of air that came through the hinges, could be toxic.
这些是美根的衣服
These are Megan's.
如果你想穿的话
If you want them.
我认得出那女人的车
I recognize that woman's car.
她叫莱斯利，我记得
Her name was Leslie, I think.
你认识她？
You knew her?
是个邻居
She was a neighbor.
艾米特不是唯一一个知道这里的人
Emmett wasn't the only one that knew about this place.
如果有其他幸存者 他们可能也会来这里
If any others somehow survived, they could be coming here too.
星期五，善良和大方都是过时的
As of Friday, kindness and generosity are antiquated customs.
我需要缝针
I'm going to need some stitches.
你要我帮你？
Why, you want me to..?
这是你干的好事，对吧？
This is your doing, isn't it?
我意思是我怕我做不来
I mean, I don't think I'm really qualified.
我会教你的
I'll walk you through it.
过来
Here.
喝一口
Have a drink.
是什么？
What is it?
学术上说是
Technically, it's ..
伏特加
Vodka
没有毒 我自己酿的了
Safe.  I distill it myself.
我只是说这酒是我自己酿的，但我不保证味道
- I just said I distill it, I didn't say anything about it tasting good.
嗯，这就真难喝
Yeah, that's awful.
你冰一下，会好喝点的
You want it on the rocks.
我年轻的时候驻扎在船上 没什么事 研究的这个小技巧
Little trick I taught myself as a young man stationed on a ship, with way too much free time.
有时候 指挥官安排的人物太多 我会冰上一两杯偷偷的喝
Every now and again, if the CO was working us too hard. We'd freeze and snap the knob off..
然后把浴室把手敲坏 里面还有人的
the bathroom door while they were still inside.
那要一两个小时才能出来吧
I guess it took an hour or two, to get out
够了
I'm good.
那你自便 我喝了
Suit yourself.  Cheers.
这很干净
This is clean.
你只管缝针就是了
All you need to do is .. stitch.
真有两下子
You're doing fine.
这是从你车上拿出来的
Stuff I grabbed from your car.
估计是还没来得及用
Didn't have time to bring in the booze.
这很遗憾
Sadly.
全都在这吗？
What is all that?
我想做服装设计
I wanted to design clothes.
怪不得你针线活那么好
No wonder you were so good with the stiches.
美根想做艺术家
Megan wanted to be an artist.
- 她是你女儿吗？ - 嗯
- She was your daughter? - Yeah
她很聪明 喜欢看书 看杂志 有时候看书是为了放松心情
She was smart, loved to read, the magazines or just for fun.
她喜欢关于巴黎的书
She inhaled books. Anything with Paris.
她喜欢那里的电影和文化
She liked their movies. Their culture, you know.
有时候我跟她开玩笑，我问她
We used to have this little joke, every once in a while, I'd ask her..
你长大后要做什么？
What do you want to be when you grow up?
你猜她怎么回答？
And you know what she'd say?
她说要做法国人
French.
不管怎么样
Anyway,
她妈妈还是带她离开了
Her mother turned her against me.
她们去了芝加哥
Took her off to Chicago.
人类真是奇怪的生物
People are strange creatures
不管怎么说都不听 他们不知道外面的世界有多危险
You can't always convince them that safety is in their own  best interest
你知道吗 都过去了
You don't know they're gone.
不管怎样
Anyway,
至少我帮过她们
At least I tried to help them.
嘿，知道吗 无论你怎么做 那女人都活不了
Hey, you know there is nothing you could've done for that woman
就算是你带她进来了 她还是会死的
Even if you had let her in, she still would've died.
你是后悔了吗
You asked earlier about .. regrets,
我有点后悔了
Yeah, I got some of those.
我们俩总算想一块了
Welcome to the club.
我是说 我生活在一个小圈子里
I mean, I lived my life in a 40-mile radius.
但 我跟肯定 一切都是天意
And that was by design, I made sure that happened.
高中时我很能跑
I was so fast in high school,
但成绩却差得很
I even managed to outrun my bad grades.
我曾经是州代表运动员
I was all-state track,
而且是连续三年
Three years in a row.
我拿过路易斯安娜理工大学的全额奖学金
Caught a full ride to Louisiana Tech up there in Ruston.
我记得 输家的最后两个星期里
I remember I spent the last two weeks of that summer,
我向别人炫耀学校寄给我的共车票 只要想看 都可以看的
Showing off the bus ticket they sent me, to anybody who looked at it
去学校的前一晚
And then came the night before I was supposed to leave,
我很担心
And I just got so worried,
我不知道到了那里要干嘛
About how bad I was going to do up there
毕竟那里人才辈出
With all those smart kids
所以我堕落了
So I went out of my way
整天喝酒 喝到不省人事
To get just pissed wasted, so bad that
每天早上都起不来床
There was no chance I was waking up in in the morning.
所以 我就搭不上巴士
So I missed the bus
赶不上第一班 下一班也就不搭了
I didn't buy a ticket for the next one
在下一班也一样
Or the one after that.
如果你搭上了 你可能已经死掉了
Well, if you'd gone, you might be dead now.
是啊 我很幸运 对吧
Well, lucky me, right?
我们都一样幸运
Lucky us.
几年前
A few, a few years ago,
我还住在五金店里
I was at a hardware store
那时 店里来了个男的 带着他女儿
And there was this little girl, with her Dad.
那男的走的快 小女孩跟不上
And he was in a hurry, and she wasn't keeping up.
于是
and he kept
那男的就很恨的拽着小女孩的胳膊 拖着她走
yanking on her arm, really hard, you know.
太过分了
too hard.
你知道那是什么感觉吗？
You know that feeling?
当我爸爸想拽我手的时候 我哥哥科林总是在我身边
When my Dad got that way, my brother Collin was always there.
还拼命的挖苦我 好让爸爸拽我
To take the worst of it. For me.
看到那个小女孩后 我想 也许我可以
And after seeing that little girl, I thought maybe I could
帮一下
do that
那个女孩
For her.
可是 我只是眼睁睁的看着她
But I just kept watching
他们要离开的时候 我还是什么都没做
And they were about to leave, and I'd done nothing.
但是
And,
小女孩溜出去了
she slips
那男的很生气 于是就打小女该
And it throws him out off-balance and he hits her
我很想帮那个小女孩
And I wanted so badly to do something.
帮她脱困 但
To help her, but
每当遇到困难时
I do what I always do when things get hard
我都会逃避
I just panicked and ran.
听着
Look,
我们还在这 我们还活着
We're here, we're alive.
只要还活着就好
And that means something.
懂了吗？
got it?
有没有搞错
You've got to be kidding me.
什么？
What?
这里缺了几块
We're missing pieces here.
看着可怜的小猫
Look at this poor cat.
都变畸形猫了 成独眼猫了
He's been deformed, he's got one eye.
这猫还要潜水呢 就是少了一只眼睛
About to go snorkling and everything too.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
喔 世界末日的时尚  呵呵
Ooh, cornering the market on post-apocalyptic fashion, huh?
我需要更多斧头和锯
Needs more axes and chainsaws.
做什么用 她有枪
For what, she has a shotgun.
是 但要是在那儿的话 就...
Yeah, what if up there it's like..
- 有踪迹吗？ - 笨蛋
-  tracks? - Zombies.
连霍华德都不认为 那是有可能的
Though even Howard doesn't think that one's possible.
你真应该听听他的关于突变空间蠕虫的理论
Though you should hear his theory about mutant space-worms.
那是什么？霍华德？
What is that? Howard?
保持镇定 我们很安全
Stay calm. We're okay.
那是什么？ - 安静
- What was that? - Quiet.
听起来像是直升飞机
That sounds like helicopters.
也许是部队的 但不是我们的
Could be military. But not ours.
你怎么能确定？
How can you tell?
- 我当了14年的海军 - 那里发生了什么事？
- 14 years in the Navy. - What's happening up there?
我猜 那些光已经笼罩了这里
My guess, those flashes that kicked this all off,
那只是第一阶段
That was phase 1.
往敌方集中区域攻击 强火力攻击 马上
Take out your opponent's population centers, with big hits, all at once
快点 继续第二轮
Fast. And then for round 2.
扫射
Ground sweeps.
最近的卫星记录显示编码的流通量有所增加
The satellite log shows an increase in coded traffic recently.
可能是外星信号吧
Possibly extra-terrestrial signals.
我想我们刚刚听到的声音是空中巡逻队
I bet what we just heard were air-borne patrols sent to hunt down
在搜寻像我们这样残存的生命
the remaining signs of life. Like us.
也许吧 兄弟
Okay, oh boy..
那就糟了
That's bad.
更糟糕的是
And that's worse.
那边有什么吗？
What was up there?
空气过滤系统
Air filtration system.
我够不到它 有什么东西挡住了
I can't.. something is blocking the hedge.
如果我们不能把它拿回来，我们很快就会用完空气中的氧气
If we can't get it back up, we're gonna run out of breathable air fast.
你是唯一一个能拿到的人
You're the only one small enough to reach it.
拿到什么？
Reach what?
空气过滤器 通过这根主管道
The filtration system. Through there, the main duct.
得有人去那里  然后开启他
Someone needs to get in there and re-start it.
帮我个忙
Give me a hand.
- 让我去把 - 你不合适 搭把手 她会没事的
- Let me go in,- You won't fit, plus your arm. She'll be fine.
现在 重启系统 你只需要来回的转动手柄
Now, to re-start the unit, you just swing the handle off and on. Off and on.
像这样
That should do it.
如果你被卡住了 我们没有办法进去帮你
And neither of us will be able to go in and help you if you get stuck.
别卡住了
Don't get stuck.
米歇尔？
Michelle?
一切还好吗？
Everything okay up there?
像个死胡同
Looks like a dead end.
那是斜的
That's the incline.
翻过它 差不多就到了
Climb up that, and you're almost there.
噢，该死的
Oh, this sucks.
救命
'HELP'
发生什么事了？
What's wrong?
他骗了你 他骗了梅甘
He lied to you, he lied about Megan.
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
我觉得他对她做了什么
I think he did something horrible to her.
怎么可能？
How?.
他的家人在很多年前已经搬去芝加哥了
His family moved to Chicago years ago.
这是什么？
What's this?
这是血吗？
Is that blood?
跟我来
Come with me.
等等 这是..
Wait, is that..
都上新闻了 所有人都以为她只是离开了
It was on the news and everything. Most people just thought she skipped town.
她失踪了 两年后又回来了
She went missing, two years back.
我这有条信息
There is a message up there.
在玻璃窗上用血写着 “救命”
It said 'HELP'. It was scratched on the inside of the window.
还有一只耳环
This earring was with it.
在她失踪后 有没有再出现过
Did she ever show up, after she went missing?
他对我说 他当着我面说 他说这是他女儿
He said to me, he said to my face. He said this is his daughter, he said this...
他带走她并杀了她
He took her and he killed her.
我以为
I was just thinking,
也许我们
Maybe we
把他的枪带走
take away his gun
把他绑起来 去坦白他做的罪行 - 什么 向谁坦白 警察吗？
Tie him up, to confess. Whatever it is he's done - What confess to who, the police?
看 正如我说的
Look, like I said,
我们不可能是唯一的幸存者 对吗？
We can't be the only survivors, right?
- 这个女人 师徒走的更远一些 对吗？ - 是的 直到死去
- The woman, she was able to get around a little, right? -- Yeah, till she died.
在我们正上方 窒息而死
Directly above us, choking to death.
还有其他人活下来吗
Other people to save
现在 那是团队工作的好榜样
Now, that's a great example of teamwork.
完成的很好 就像一些音乐
Very well done. Feel like some music.
解决问题总汇让我产生一种音乐的感觉
Problem solving always puts me in a musical mood.
米歇尔
Michelle,
你应该洗个澡 以防万一
You should go shower, just in case.
好的
Sure
我想我有个主意
I think I might have an idea.
- 十条设计刘海的好办法 - 不 不是文章 是这个
- '10 Better Ways to Style My Bangs'? - No, not the article.  This.
我想我可以做一个
I think I can only make one.
但那只是个开始
But it's a start.
不是开玩笑的
No kidding.
嘿 霍华德
Hey, Howard
这是什么 你再看 16根蜡烛 吗
What is this? You're re-watching '16 Candles'?
粉红色更漂亮
'Pretty in Pink'
这是梅甘最喜欢的电影  我能帮你什么吗？
It was one of Megan's favorite movies. Can I help you with something?
不 不用了 我只是在弄一些水
No, no, I'm just grabbing some water.
说 呃
Say, ahmm,
你知道 我只是在想
You know, I was just thinking..
不是 我试着告诉你如何操作这个地方
Not, that I'm trying to tell you how to run this place.
但是 我只是
But I am just,
有点担心
a bit curious
米歇尔
about Michelle
你觉得她能到达离空气过滤系统多远的地方
Say, how close do you think she got to the air filtration unit?
你觉得她已经拿到它了吗？
You think she touched it?
是的 我非常确定她碰过了
Yeah, I'm pretty sure she touched it.
是 我知道她后来还清理了所有的事 ... 但我只是觉得
Yeah, I know she cleaned up after, and everything.. But I'm just thinking..
假如那个净化装置不知道被外界怎么样了
Given that unit filter has got god knows what from outside
如果他追踪所有的事情 那将是非常集中精神
If she tracked anything back in with her. It would be pretty concentrated
而且
And
会弄得 淋浴 水槽 卫生间哪里都是
Could be all over the shower, and the sink, bathroom, right now.
不管怎样 这只是一个假设
Well, anyways, it's just a thought.
目前都很好 伙计
Not bad so far, partner.
如果霍华德找到这个 他会杀了我们的
If Howard find this, he's going to kill us.
好吧 所以 我们把他的枪拿走
Alright, so, we get the gun away from him,
把他绑起来 确定他不能到处乱走
Tie him up, make sure he isn't going anywhere.
然后我们其中一人
And then one of us
应该...
just..
出去找救援
Goes out, and looks for help.
第一个词
Ahmm, first word..
娇小..
tiny..
侏儒..
Small, pygmie..
- 娇小 - 是的
- Little. - Yup.
那么 好
Alright, ahh
第二个词
Second word,
Michelle, is a..
呃 女孩
ahmm, girl
呃 一个女孩 一个儿童
hmm, a girl, a child
啊 一个女孩
ahh, a girl.
不 她没有那么小 所以她是一个
No, she's older, so she is a..
她有点公主型
A little princess?
那也不是 它是
ahh, No.  It was ..
女人
Woman.
小女人
'Little Women'..
好吧
Well,
一个小女人
a little woman,
接下来
Next time,
再说的具体点
Try to be a little more .. specific.
我一直在观察
I'm always watching
一直都是
Always.
呃  上帝
ahmm, god.
我去任何我想去的地方
I go wherever I want.
我的 意思  是我不知道
I mean, ah, I don't know.
我知道你在做什么 我看到了
I know what you're doing, I see what you're doing.
我知道你的所作所为
I know what you're up to.
听着 霍华德 我不知道在暗示什么
Look, Howard. I don't know what you're getting at,
我知道你什么时候睡觉
I see when you're sleeping
- 我真的不知道你到底 ... - 我知道你在做什么
- I don't know, what... - I know what you're doing,
- 啊 我不知道 - 而且我一直在观察 从没停止过
- ahh, I don't know.. - and I'm always watching. Always watching.
圣诞老人 你是圣诞老人
Santa Claus. You're Santa Claus.
是的 米歇尔 非上好
Yeah, Michelle, that's great.
好的 我想接下来轮到艾米特了
Okay, except it was Emmett's turn.
- 好的 我有点激动.. - 嗯 我也是
- Yeah, I got a little excited... - well, I'm keeping that point.
总的来说 这都是你努力得来的
Totally, you earned it.
艾米特？
Emmett?
嘿
Hey,
我有些事情需要你帮忙
I need your help with something.
没问题
Sure.
你是下一个 准备好
You.  On deck.
这是什么
What is this?
一个桶
A barrel.
把它抬到浴室去
Move it into the bathroom.
这是硫酸
This is sulphoric acid.
你们俩有谁知道那是什么
Do either of you know what that is?
这通常是
It's usually produced
制作高氧酸纳的原材料
as a precursor to ammonium proclorate.
燃料.
Fuel.
Used to launch naval cell like the ones in North Harvard
Used to launch naval cell like the ones in North Harvard.[???]
具有很强的腐蚀性
It's highly corrosive.
能分解与它接触的大多生物材料
Dissolves most biological material on contact.
用到人身上
With humans,
能分解的只剩骨头
Right down to the bone.
嘿 霍华德 额
Hey, Howard, ahh..
你给我们看这个干嘛
What're you showing it to us this for?
你觉得我是白痴么
You think I'm an idiot?
霍华德 拜托了 你得告诉我你到底是什么意思
Howard, please, you're going to have to tell us what you're talking about.
我的意思是除掉一些垃圾
I'm talking about getting rid of some waste.
告诉我你俩想用这个做什么
Tell me what you two were doing with this.
告诉我你们两个在计划什么 就现在说
You tell me what you two were planning. Right now!
放轻松，冷静点
Take it easy, Calm down.
拜托了霍华德  - 我在给你一个机会
- Howard, please. - I'm giving you one chance.
霍华德 冷静点
Howard, just calm down.
一个机会
One chance!
好好地回答我的问题 不然我向上帝保证
to answer with some dignity or I swear to god
你进入这个桶里 活生生的体验硫酸是什么感觉
You're going into this barrel while you're alive to feel it.
是我
It was me.
跟他没有关系 都是我一个人干的
Alright, not her, It was just me.
-不不 - 跟你没关系 她说的那些话是
- No, no -- Stay out of this. She doesn't have a clue
无稽之谈
what she's talking about.
我那时候想要抢
I wanted your gun.
所以我就
And so I was,
想着弄一个武器
Thinking about making a weapon
得到它
To get it,
从你那里
From you.
我想让她像尊敬你一样尊敬我
I want her to respect me, the way she respects you.
我不是说我是对的
I'm not saying I was right, okay?
并且我很抱歉
And I'm sorry.
-你很抱歉 - 我很抱歉
- You're sorry? - I am sorry.
我接受你的道歉
I accept your apology.
他当时要伤害咱们 伤害你
He was going to hurt us. He was going to hurt you.
没事 没什么大不了的
It's okay, this is okay.
这是 事情原来的样子
This is the way it was always supposed to be.
你现在安全了
You're safe now.
现在只有你和我
Now, it's just you and me.
没关系
It's okay.
现在 回到你的房间去 立刻
Now, you should go to your room now.
这不是你该看的东西
This is not part of anything you need to see.
米歇尔
Michelle?
嘿
Hey,
我以为今晚我们能有点变化呢
I thought we'd change things up tonight.
吃饭前，吃点甜品
And have dessert before dinner.
毕竟现在我们想做什么都可以了
After all, we can do whatever we want now.
你想要甜筒，还是碗装的
Would you like a cone or a bowl?
梅根总是要碗装的
Megan always wanted hers a bowl.
甜筒在邋遢了
the cones are too messy.
我知道这不是你想要的生活
I know this is not the life you prefer.
住在这下面对你来说也不容易
And it isn't easy for you living down here.
我希望我们能组成一个快乐的家庭
But I want us to be a happy family.
你和我
You and me.
房间已经收拾好了
The mess is all taken care of.
放轻松 我去准备晚饭
So, just hang loose, and I'll go get dinner started.
一切还好吗
Everything alright?
嗯 我正要看会书
Yeah, I was just about to do some reading.
我准备布置桌子了
It's time to set the table.
晚饭做好了
Supper is ready.
嗯- 好的
- Yeah. - Okay.
保持住 我也不知道为什么
Keeps doing that. I don't know why.
米歇尔 这个为什么这么松
Michelle, Why is this loose?
起来
Get up.
- 为什么 -起来
- Why? - Get up.
从床垫上下载 现在
Get off the matress. Now!
草，该死
Oh, shit.
你要从我身上踏过去,才能出去
You're going to walk out on me?
在我救了你之后
After I saved you?
保护你安全
And kept you safe?
你就这么回报我
This is how you re-pay me?
不是的
No
这才是
This is.
米歇尔
Michelle!
你不知道外面有什么
You don't know what's out there.
你逃不掉的
You can't run from them.
和我呆在一起
Stay with me.
来吧
Come on.
救命 我在这呢 救命
Help!  I'm out here, help!
噢  我操
Oh, fuck.
如果你们接受过医学训练或者有作战经验
But if you have any medical training Or combat experience
我们需要帮忙
We need help
在休斯敦 还有人
There are people in Houston.
在梅西医院有幸存者
There are survivors in Mercy Hospital
重复 休斯顿有人需要帮助
Repeat, there are people in Houston Who need our help
来加入我们吧
Come join us
我们已经收回南部海岸了
We've taken back the Southern seaboard
我们要赢了
And we're winning.
如果你受过医学训练或者有作战经验
If you have any medical training Or combat experience
还有幸存者
There's survivors